<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pablo Marcos&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Pablo Marcos&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courage</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/courage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/courage/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes feel like a tree, standing right by the cliff, having survived to all of this.
I sometimes feel like a rock, standing high and standing tall, fighting against all odds.
I sometimes feel like a mountain, big, old, and sometimes even broken.
I feel alone most often.
But like a rock and like a tree, like a mountain and the sea, this too shall pass. I too shall understand, once the healing breeze of time lets the first grey hairs settle on my forehead, that all of this was not in vain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoK Final Status Report</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-final-status-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 01:30:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-final-status-report/</guid>
      <description>For the Season of KDE 2021, I decided to work on Okular&amp;rsquo;s website. Okular is a multifaceted program that I use almost every day for my PDF reading and annotating needs, although it can do much more. Sadly, its website was a bit outdated and not mobile friendly. I thus proposed to rewrite the Okular website using the HUGO framework, in a similar way as was done with the kde.org main website, and keeping consistency with other KDE applications such as Konsole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoK 2021 April Report</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 14:45:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-april/</guid>
      <description>All work on the project was finished in march, so all that is left is some minor modifications and writing the project report. I believe that the goals set at the start of the project have been mostly fulfilled: the project does in fact present the information in a clear and beautiful, mobile-friendly way, thanks to the aether-sass theme. It has google-independent search, although it does not use lunar.js as was suggested, and the development news are now in its own section, although the changelogs were left outside of the individual posts for practicality reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoK 2021 March Report</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 19:40:00 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-march/</guid>
      <description>In the february post, I mentioned how I ordered the material that was on Carl Schwan&amp;rsquo;s MVP for the Index page, explaining Okular&amp;rsquo;s main features. Now that that was set, I had to add support for i18n, as it can be difficult for translators to work with a raw html template. This was achieved by using the {{i18n}} HUGO template, which specifies the translatable parts by using {{ i18n &amp;quot;Section.variable&amp;quot; }} in each of the strings to translate, and then mapping the values into a yaml file such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoK 2021 February Report</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-february/</guid>
      <description>I started the month by porting the Anouncements section from Raw HTML to Markdown, for which I wrote a small python script that parses all the content in this news.rdf file, inherited from the old site, and creates several markdown post files that will be processed by the list and single templates of the aether-sass theme into the new section.
 To see the full python script, click here import re text_file = open(&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SoK 2021 January Report</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/season-of-kde-2021/sok-report-january/</guid>
      <description>I havent done much this January, as it was the &amp;ldquo;partiels&amp;rdquo; (final exams) month at INSA and I was really caught up studying. I did, however, find time to write the project application, which I have attached below for reference, and I spent what little time I was able to devote to SoK learning how to properly use HUGO and which templates I had to edit to get a given, desired result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPM Language Center Poster Contest</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/centrodelenguas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/centrodelenguas/</guid>
      <description>I participated in the I POSTER COMPETITION at UPM&amp;rsquo;s Language Center, whose theme was: &amp;ldquo;Foreign languages and you: how they have influenced your life&amp;rdquo;. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t win, I think I got a cute and original poster, which is what I wanted; for another year, I&amp;rsquo;ll check Unsplash better before making decisions 🤓.
Here is my poster:
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Wine and Oil Label Competition at ETSIAAB</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/vinoyaceite2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/concursos/vinoyaceite2020/</guid>
      <description>I was a finalist in the 2020 Wine and Oil Label Design Contest of the ETSIAAB, in which I participated with the help of my cousin, Daniel Marcos, who helped me design the wine label, and Marta Pérez, who helped me with the oil label.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If ants rose up</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/if-ants-rose-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/if-ants-rose-up/</guid>
      <description>If ants rose up, they would take over your room. They would march like silent sentinels, through their hidden passages and their obscure tunnels, down into the deepest realms of yourself.
If ants rose up, there&amp;rsquo;d be no windows or doors to shut; no chains, no pains, no frosts and no repellents; there&amp;rsquo;d be grains, and seeds, and those who opposed them would be at their knees.
 This post was published disconnected on mastodon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Revoy&#39;s Cats</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/david-revoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/david-revoy/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so: There&amp;rsquo;s nothing cuter than @davidrevoy &amp;lsquo;s cat generator! You should definetely give it a try! You can see mine below hehe.
https://www.peppercarrot.com/extras/html/2016_cat-generator/index.php?seed=seedname
Found it via @mmu_man
#art #cuteness #cats #CatsOfMastodon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philantropy, they say</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/philanthropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/philanthropy/</guid>
      <description>‘Philanthropy’, they say, they who killed my family without an afterthought; ‘philanthropy’, those who destroy the forests and crush dreams. ‘Philanthropy’, and a grin, while they mercilessly unleash the rage of the gods.
Some open the Gates, others offer you the Golden Apple of Iðunn; both wash their hands in the water they’ve stolen. But their hands are stained with blood, and the more they wash, the more they poison, the ghost of christmas future hanging over their heads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/erase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/erase/</guid>
      <description>This text, or at least a very similar one, I wrote it around November 2015, that&amp;rsquo;s why I have put this date; however, the photo is much later, from Villalba in 2020. Curiously, I wrote it to prepare myself for the First Certificate in English, although my teacher didn&amp;rsquo;t like very much that it was so dramatic 😅😅. But that&amp;rsquo;s ok, I&amp;rsquo;m better now :D
 Lara saw something unusual in the grass and went back to take a closer look.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml ``` [outputs] home = [&amp;ldquo;HTML&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;JSON&amp;rdquo;] ```</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>