<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Poems on Pablo Marcos&#39; Blog</title>
    <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Poems on Pablo Marcos&#39; Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Courage</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/courage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/courage/</guid>
      <description>I sometimes feel like a tree, standing right by the cliff, having survived to all of this.
I sometimes feel like a rock, standing high and standing tall, fighting against all odds.
I sometimes feel like a mountain, big, old, and sometimes even broken.
I feel alone most often.
But like a rock and like a tree, like a mountain and the sea, this too shall pass. I too shall understand, once the healing breeze of time lets the first grey hairs settle on my forehead, that all of this was not in vain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If ants rose up</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/if-ants-rose-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/if-ants-rose-up/</guid>
      <description>If ants rose up, they would take over your room. They would march like silent sentinels, through their hidden passages and their obscure tunnels, down into the deepest realms of yourself.
If ants rose up, there&amp;rsquo;d be no windows or doors to shut; no chains, no pains, no frosts and no repellents; there&amp;rsquo;d be grains, and seeds, and those who opposed them would be at their knees.
 This post was published disconnected on mastodon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David Revoy&#39;s Cats</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/david-revoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/david-revoy/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so: There&amp;rsquo;s nothing cuter than @davidrevoy &amp;lsquo;s cat generator! You should definetely give it a try! You can see mine below hehe.
https://www.peppercarrot.com/extras/html/2016_cat-generator/index.php?seed=seedname
Found it via @mmu_man
#art #cuteness #cats #CatsOfMastodon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philantropy, they say</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/philanthropy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/philanthropy/</guid>
      <description>‘Philanthropy’, they say, they who killed my family without an afterthought; ‘philanthropy’, those who destroy the forests and crush dreams. ‘Philanthropy’, and a grin, while they mercilessly unleash the rage of the gods.
Some open the Gates, others offer you the Golden Apple of Iðunn; both wash their hands in the water they’ve stolen. But their hands are stained with blood, and the more they wash, the more they poison, the ghost of christmas future hanging over their heads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Escape</title>
      <link>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/erase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.pablomarcos.me/posts/poesia/erase/</guid>
      <description>This text, or at least a very similar one, I wrote it around November 2015, that&amp;rsquo;s why I have put this date; however, the photo is much later, from Villalba in 2020. Curiously, I wrote it to prepare myself for the First Certificate in English, although my teacher didn&amp;rsquo;t like very much that it was so dramatic 😅😅. But that&amp;rsquo;s ok, I&amp;rsquo;m better now :D
 Lara saw something unusual in the grass and went back to take a closer look.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>